Mariaclaudia Nicolai

Pharmacy student and passionate about technology



About

I am an Italian pharmacy student with knowledge in both chemistry and biology. I built my pharmaceutical background by studying at the University of Salerno. After the curricular internship in the pharmacy, I started working on my experimental thesis. I focused on the identification of a novel antimicrobial peptide activity model using machine learning algorithms. Meanwhile, I collaborated with TU Delft for a research project. Finally, to express the passion for technology, I co-founded the LPSystems B.V., a company specialized in designing embedded devices.

Personal info:

Contacts

Via San Leucio 82100 Benevento Italy +39 349 12 00 304 mariaclaudia.nicolai @gmail.com

ORCID

0000-0001-9270-8564

Publication indexes

https://Google Scholar

Languages

Italian: Native speaker English: Good

Highlights

09.2013 present	MSc. in Pharmacy Thesis subject: Identification of a novel antimicrobial peptide activity model by machine learning and its use to build new peptide sequences	University of Salerno Italy
07.2018 05.2019	Visiting (research) Research subject: Role of users' feedback on healthcare mobile Android apps	TU Delft The Netherlands
05.2018 11.2018	Internship (curricular) Internship subject: Ethical and deontological aspects of the profession of pharmacist and applications of the notions acquired during the study	Farmacia Dr. Italiano Italy
2015 2016	Collaboration (work) Work subject: Manual handling of precision	Bruitparif France

Education

2013-present Master degree in Pharmacy (31 of 32 exams)

electronic tools

Organization University of Salerno, Italy

Thesis "Identification of a novel antimicrobial peptide activity model by machine

learning"

Tutor Prof. Dr. Stefano Piotto

Grants

2015-2016 **Scholarship**

Internship

05.2018-11.2018 Internship (curricular)

Farmacia Dr. Ugo Italiano s.a.s. Benevento, Italy

Tutor Dr. Stefano Italiano

Scientific research

Workshop WAMA 2019 "Healthcare Android Apps: A Tale of the Customers' Perspective"

In Proceedings of 3rd International Workshop on App Market Analytics

Presented at ACM Joint European Software Engineering Conference Tallinn, Estonia

Work experience

2015-2016 Collaboration

Bruitparif Paris, France

Company details Bruitparif is a non-profit environmental organization responsible for

monitoring the environmental noise in the Paris agglomeration

Contribution Testing of electronic devices, handling precision electronic tools

2019-present Co-founder (LPSystems)

Company details LPSystems B.V. designs low-cost professional audio broadcasting equipment

Acquired skills

Software skills

Languages Python, HTML

Tools GMDH, YASARA, KNIME, LaTeX, Git

Lab skills

Lab techniques Conducting and supporting scientific investigations and experiments

Planning, setting up and undertaking controlled experiments and trials

Recording and analyzing data, demonstrating procedures

Presenting results to senior staff

Writing reports, reviews, and summaries

Good teamwork skills

Equipment Safety goggles and safety equipment

Beakers, flasks, funnels, graduated cylinders, droppers, pipettes,

thermometers, Bunsen burners, balances